martinjosephgormley@gmail.com martygormley.com github.com/martyjg linkedin.com/in/martygormley +4478 4395 6541



Profile

My drive for web development derives from my enjoyment of problem-solving, the opportunity of learning how to tackle these problems from different perspectives and the satisfaction of making quality products. I'm searching for a position where I can work and learn creatively in a progressive and modern team.

Skills

Proficient with...
HTML5, CSS,
JavaScript (ES2015,
TypeScript), React,
Node, Express,
Angular, PostCSS,
LESS, SASS, Git

Experience with...
Express, Hapi,
Jasmine, Ruby, PHP,
behat, Wordpress,
Gulp

Currently playing with... Ember, Arduino, Processing, Tidal

Experience

Bureau for Visual Affairs - Front End Web Developer | February 2017 - present At the BfVA (Bureau for Visual affairs), I work across a range of projects (both inherited ES5 and new ES6) for clients from the cultural and commercial sector. I have gained strong experience in working with the React library and have moved to writing CSS using PostCSS and with the BAS library. I also gained experience in creating a custom user-friendly CMS according to our clients' wishes in Wordpress. In my time at BfVA I learned to work in tight sprints, and the necessity of being aware of my own timespans and those of my colleagues (other devs, designers, clients). I was fortunate to have this position in a small team where development is fluid and allows for peer-review and pair-programming when needed.

The Mill - Front End Web Developer | April 2016 - February 2017
Going full-time with The Mill meant I was given my own front-end project to work on, alongside assisting the team's lead Front End Developer with another project. Across these projects I've gained experience with testing (Selenium, phantomJS, behat, geminiJS, aXe accessibility testing), CSS preprocessors (SASS, LESS) and ReactJS

The Mill - Web Development/Design Intern | February 2016 - April 2016 My internship at The Mill gave me a taste of every position in a development team and introduced me to real experience in an agile development process. Working closely with the team's designer helped develop my UX design skills and has aided me greatly in discussing a product's planning.

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive | July 2015 - December 2015 The intensive course involves twelve weeks of taught lessons which range across everything necessary to get on the technical level of a Junior Developer. The projects I completed during the course allowed me to experience the process of conceptualisation, planning, development and deployment. The course has given me experience of an agile process and git/github. Most importantly, WDI has given me the tools to teach myself any new technology with confidence.

Unicorns In Tech - Events and Community Manager | October 2014 - June 2015 Organising the Unicorns In Tech community gave me experience of working alone and in a team to see large project through from start to completion. Arranging speakers and seeking new members provided me with an insight into the tech and startup world.

Education

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive | July 2015 - Present Goldsmiths College (UoL) - BSc Psychology | September 2011 - July 2014 Lumen Christi College - A*AAB at A-level | September 2009 - June 2011

Interests

Outside of programming, I like music, film, video games and hanging out. For weekend fun I'm always on the lookout for new cafes, bars and parties so please send any tips my way.